<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Handyman</title>
    <link>http://data-handyman.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Handyman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://data-handyman.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Gmail - part 1 and 1/2</title>
      <link>http://data-handyman.com/post/simplgmail15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://data-handyman.com/post/simplgmail15/</guid>
      <description>That Darn App password Last time, in Simple Gmail - part 1, I talked about how I wanted Python to interact with Gmail so that data from the contact form could be organized. I really only went over how to provide the initial set up for Python/Gmail interaction. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like all of the set up that was required, and thought that I could automate this process.
For the past couple of weeks, I have been working on a Python library called simplgmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Gmail - part 1</title>
      <link>http://data-handyman.com/post/simplgmail1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://data-handyman.com/post/simplgmail1/</guid>
      <description>Gmail and Python In the last post I mentioned that I wanted to organize the data received from the contact form. If you don&amp;rsquo;t remember, the important thing to know is that the form on my Contact page is sent to my Gmail account via a service called Formspree.
To do this automatically, I will use Python, my favorite programming language. Getting Python to interact with Gmail was not too difficut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formspree?</title>
      <link>http://data-handyman.com/post/formspree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://data-handyman.com/post/formspree/</guid>
      <description>Why Formspree? Creating a form itself isn&amp;rsquo;t too complicated or interesting to me. What interests me about creating forms is the &amp;lsquo;action&amp;rsquo; taken once you press the submit button.
I want to be able to respond to the person who is contacting me. So, the &amp;lsquo;action&amp;rsquo; I am looking for the form to take is to email. In a later section, I want to go over organizing this data, but the first step is receiving it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://data-handyman.com/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://data-handyman.com/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome to data-handyman.com I&amp;rsquo;m glad you came to look at my web site!
The purpose of this site is to let you know about the ways that a data handyman can help your data related projects.
I want you to see how your project can benefit from topics discussed on this site, what has benefited me, and how to do more with less.
I want to make your life easier by helping you think out of the box and realizing how you can make your data related processes more efficient, effective, cost less and deliver more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>http://data-handyman.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://data-handyman.com/contact/</guid>
      <description> Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about your data-related project!  --  Submit   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you!</title>
      <link>http://data-handyman.com/thankyou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://data-handyman.com/thankyou/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll talk soon! Thank you for your message!
I am really looking forward to reading what you have to say.
I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to respond to you quickly, and hopefully we can begin working out how a data handyman can help you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>